漫威电视出品
哈莱姆天堂
我们离门很近  冲过去吧
We are ten feet from the door. Just bust through.
我没法从各个角度保护你  你是目标
I can't cover you from every angle. You're the target.
-该死  -按住
- Oh, shit. - Hold this.
克莱尔
Claire.
-怎么回事  -凯奇  吧台后面
- What's going on here? - Cage. Behind the bar.
他不怕子弹吧
He's bulletproof, ain't he?
她怕  先打她
She ain't. Shoot her first.
那拖不了他们太久
That's not gonna hold 'em long.
不
No.
他们堵住了门  没法进去
They barricaded the door and shit. There's no way through.
别管凯奇了
Forget Cage.
警察们过几分钟就会冲进来
The cops are gonna flood this place in a minute.
不  我们不走
No. We're staying.
谁都不许走  直到我们抓住他们
Nobody leaves. Not until we have them.
你在说什么  威利斯
What you talking about, Willis?
你现在还想开玩笑吗
You got jokes? Right now?
开玩笑的是你
You're the one who's joking
如果你觉得我们不用计划就能逃走
if you think that we're escaping here without a plan.
待会再讨论之前预想的计划吧
Later for that pre-written shit.
有时你得随心而为
Sometimes you gotta freestyle.
你只剩一枚犹大子弹了
Look, you got one Judas bullet left.
万一让卢克·凯奇抢占先机了呢
What are you gonna do if Luke Cage takes you head on?
我看上去像担心的样子吗
Do I look worried?
不  这才是问题所在
No. That's the problem.
这地方密不透风  连后门也封锁了
Place is airtight. Back is sealed off, too.
所以没有其他出路
So there's no other way out?
-是的  泰抓到了一名流浪者  -很好
- No. Ty caught a straggler. - Good.
只要不是我们的人  就是我们的人质
Anybody ain't us is a hostage.
确保谁都不能看到我
Make sure none of them look me in the eye.
洛佩斯  糖糖  你们看住
Lopes, Sugar, you're babysitting.
把他们转移到那边  面朝墙壁
Move 'em up there and face them towards the wall.
胆敢抵抗就蒙住他们的眼睛
Anybody resists, blindfold 'em.
胆敢多嘴就直接杀死
Too much lip, shoot 'em in the head.
剩下的人自然就懂了
The rest will get the message.
放开我
Let me go!
把减肥奥巴马带到楼上来  泰
Take Diet Obama upstairs, Ty.
在我上来之前  用枪指着他
Keep a gun on him till I get up there.
放开我
Take your hands off me!
-你们不能这样  -我们可以
- You can't do this! - Yes, we can.
奇普
Zip.
你上去后  把我的钥匙给我
While you're up there, get me my key.
你知道我说的是哪一把
You know the one I'm talking about.
你叫我姓是想干什么
What the hell are you doing calling me out by my first name?
如果你觉得我们逃得掉  那简直是在做梦
You're dreaming if you think we're getting out of here.
你当着一百多人的面朝一名女警开枪
You shot a female cop in front of 100 people.
大家只会记得
All people will remember
卢克·凯奇跟金刚一样救美
is Luke Cage going all King Kong with a bitch
跳下了阳台
and jumping off a balcony.
他们会记得
What they're gonna remember
卢克·凯奇是在躲子弹
is Luke Cage running from the bullets.
外面的人只知道卢克·凯奇疯了
All they know outside is that Cage lost his mind,
发生了交火  产生了僵局
shots were fired, and it's a standoff.
未知是我们的好伙伴
Confusion is our friend.
只要我们杀了卢克和米丝蒂
We kill Luke and Misty,
我们就会摇身变成阻止哈莱姆威胁的英雄
suddenly, we're the heroes who stopped the Harlem Menace.
他们只知道  是他杀了她
For all they know, he killed her.
只要他们死  随我们怎么说
With them dead, we control the story.
那就是你的计划  就这样
That's your plan? That's it?
我们拖得越久
The bigger the stall,
就有越多时间编造其他版本
the more time we have for other diversions.
米丝蒂一定要死  我会再给凯奇来一枪
Misty will be dead, I'll have another shot at Cage,
这里还会有别的出路
and there's bound to be another way out of here.
我们能尽快离开这里
We'll cross that bridge soon enough.
我们要怎么拖住他们
Okay. How do we hold them off right now?
我是卢克·凯奇
I'm gonna be Luke Cage.
第一季  第十一集
·
卢克凯奇
卢克  我好冷
Luke, I'm cold.
-我觉得你伤到动脉了  -什么
- I think you nicked an artery. - What?
所以才失血这么快
That's why it's bleeding so fast.
我不骗你  米丝蒂
And I ain't gonna lie, Misty.
-你不会喜欢的  -什么意思
- You're not gonna like this. - What do you mean?
按住
Hold that.
我们应该从后面出去
We should just go out the back.
-他们已经派人看守了  -你怎么知道
- They've already secured it. - How do you know?
换我就会这么做  现在他想赢的唯一方式
It's what I would do. The only way he can win at this point
就是控制进出的所有人
is if he can control who comes in and who leaves.
不管怎么样  我要先带你去安全的地方
Either way, I gotta get you someplace safe.
怎么还是
What the hell?
还好这幢楼曾经是卢西亚诺的
Lucky Luciano used to own this building.
这里还有很多暗道和角落
It still has a lot of prohibition nooks and crannies.
蹲下
Sit down!
转过去  面朝墙壁
Turn around. Face the wall.
谁在帮我
Who's helping me?
是卢克·凯奇  还是卡尔·卢卡斯
Luke Cage? Or Carl Lucas?
威利斯·斯崔克是谁
Who is Willis Stryker?
他的街头绰号是响尾蛇
His street name is Diamondback.
他就是你要找的
He was the hardware connect
水腹蛇武器供应商
for Cottonmouth that you were looking for.
他还是我哥哥
He's also my half-brother.
这是你要的钥匙  老大
Here's the key you asked for, boss man.
你在干什么
What're you doing?
-我喜欢这部分  -什么
- I love this part. - What?
褪下内裤这一刻
When the panties drop.
你们家还真是够复杂的
Your family is jacked up.
哈莱姆天堂
这里一片混乱  帕特
It's chaos out here, Pat.
哈莱姆天堂
这里一片混乱  帕特
It's chaos out here, Pat.
多人受伤
Several people are injured,
大多是因为从酒吧逃出而受踩踏的伤者
mostly from the stampede to escape the club,
但是也有部分受枪伤者
but a few have gunshot wounds.
玛莉娅·迪拉德医院已经被保镖护送走
Councilwoman Mariah Dillard was whisked away by her security
大部分受伤的抗议者
and most of the injured protesters
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
大部分受伤的抗议者
and most of the injured protesters
已经紧急送往医院
have been rushed to the hospital.
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
已经紧急送往医院
have been rushed to the hospital.
反卢克·凯奇集会开始不到一小时
Less than an hour after an anti-Luke Cage rally began,
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
反卢克·凯奇集会开始不到一小时
Less than an hour after an anti-Luke Cage rally began,
卢克·凯奇本人加入其中
Luke Cage himself entered the event.
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
根据抗议者和纽约警署秘密线报
According to protesters and a confidential NYPD source,
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
根据抗议者和纽约警署秘密线报
According to protesters and a confidential NYPD source,
经验丰富的
shots rang out
哈莱姆警署梅赛德斯·奈特警探试图逮捕凯奇后
after veteran harlem police detective Mercedes Knight
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
哈莱姆警署梅赛德斯·奈特警探试图逮捕凯奇后
after veteran harlem police detective Mercedes Knight
发生了枪战
attempted to arrest Cage,
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
发生了枪战
attempted to arrest Cage,
在一段广为流传的视频中  这一危险逃犯
the dangerous fugitive who attacked two police officers
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
在一段广为流传的视频中  这一危险逃犯
the dangerous fugitive who attacked two police officers
袭击过两名警察
on a widely seen dashcam video.
突发新闻  超能力逃犯劫持人质
袭击过两名警察
on a widely seen dashcam video.
不久前  我们听到一声巨响  应该是...
And moments ago, we heard the sound of what we believe is...
我想知道爆炸是不是来自内部
I wanna know if the explosion came from the inside.
马上尽力去查
Find out what you can right away.
快给我联系米丝蒂奈特警探
And somebody get me Misty Knight.
紧急情况小队到了
ESU has just arrived.
-五分钟后我们直接进攻  -不行
- We're going tactical in five minutes. - No, you're not.
-不得行动  -我们要进去了
- Stand down. - We're going in.
目前有持枪匪徒劫持人质
We got an active shooter and a hostage situation.
他们还没提任何要求  里面还有我们的人
They haven't asked for anything and one of ours is in there.
我们需要谨慎小心
We need to be careful.
这整件事都是我说了算
This whole thing goes through me.
探长  局长的电话
Inspector, it's the chief.
局长
Yes, sir.
他不可能从后面跑了
No way he went out the back.
彻底搜查这里
Scour this whole place.
一处角落都不放过  即使是明显的地方
Every inch. Even if it's obvious.
我们这样太明目张胆了
We are making way too much noise.
他们随时可能冲进来
They're gonna bust in that door any minute.
事情变糟了
It's getting messy.
-你为什么这么担心  -因为我头脑清楚
- Why are you so shook? - 'Cause I'm clearheaded.
我头脑不清楚吗  我是闹得不小
And I'm not? Look, I'm spitting off the dome.
没错  但到目前为止我节奏很明确
It's true, but I haven't had a misplaced rhyme yet.
卢克·凯奇出现在
Violence breaks out
一个反对卢克·凯奇的集会上时  发生了暴乱
at an anti-Luke Cage rally when Luke Cage shows up?
这简直是千载难逢的机会
Come on, this shit is poetry.
-他值得我们这样吗  -当然
- Is he worth it? - Absolutely.
你跟玛莉娅谈过了吗
Did you talk to Mariah?
-她在着手准备了  -很好
- She's on it. - Good.
现在他们害怕凯奇  他们担心会死人
They're scared of Cage now. They're afraid people will die.
她会利用这点完成交易
She'll use that to close the deal.
有来电
We got a call.
-是她吗  -不是
- Is it her? - No.
是里面的固话打过来的
It's from inside. A landline.
我是纽约警署的普莉希拉·瑞德里探长
This is Inspector Priscilla Ridley from the NYPD.
请问你是哪位
Who am I speaking with?
我是达蒙·布恩
This is Damon Boone.
我收到指示  告诉你们不要靠近
I've been instructed to tell you to stay away.
卢克·凯奇把我们劫持为了人质
Luke Cage has taken us hostage
他警告说如果警察靠近
and he warns that he'll start killing people
他就开始杀人
if the police approach.
他想要什么
What does he want?
他...
He--
不可预测性可以增加我们的筹码
Unpredictability gives us leverage.
你只不过是在吓唬他们
All you're doing is scaring them.
让我帮你  你想要什么
Let me help you. What do you want?
互惠互助
Reciprocity.
局里不会有人向恐怖主义低头
No one in the department is going to bow to terrorism.
正合我意
Oh, I'm counting on that.
那个干净吗
Is that even clean?
足够做止血带了
Clean enough for a tourniquet.
你以前是童子军吗
Who were you, a Boy Scout?
特种侦察兵
Force Recon.
他们在外面肯定听到爆炸声了
They had to... hear that blast outside.
我该打给瑞德里
I should call Ridley.
该死
Oh, shit.
瑞德里探长...
-米丝蒂  -探长
- Misty? - Inspector?
-探长  -米丝蒂
- Inspector? - Misty.
-米丝蒂  -探长
- Misty. -Inspector...
你的手机在身上吗
Do you have your phone?
-我的很久以前就丢了  -该死
- I lost mine a long time ago. - Shit!
你得去楼上  知道吗
Look, you gotta go upstairs, okay?
那里的人需要你
Those people, they need you.
我不能丢下你  你会失血过多的
I can't leave you. You'll bleed out.
你会死的
You'll die.
我需要先稳定你的情况
I need to get you stabilized.
然后我会想办法
Then I'll think of some way
帮克莱尔和外面的其他人
to help Claire and everybody else up there.
你不能跟他谈判
You can't negotiate with him.
我不会的
I won't.
我不想...
I don't wanna...
我不想跟斯卡夫一样在地板上失血过多而死
I don't wanna bleed to death on the floor, like Scarfe.
有我在不会的
Not on my watch.
我应该喝一杯  议员
I think you deserve a drink, Councilman.
-我不喝酒  -你喝
- I don't drink. - Yes, you do.
没什么比得上一杯威士忌陈酿
Nothing like an aged Scotch.
要知道
You know...
如果你遇到苏格兰人
there was a time you'd cross a Scotsman...
他肯定毫不犹豫
and he wouldn't think twice
用剑把你的头砍下来
about cutting your head off with a sword.
我喜欢鼓励这种果敢的酒
I like a drink that encourages such...decisiveness.
我可以继续帮你跟他们谈判
I can help you negotiate even more.
我可以代你发言  帮你得到你想要的
I can speak for you. Get you what you want.
你看《圣经》吗  达蒙
You read the Bible, Damon?
有时候
Sometimes.
没有其它事可做时
When nothing else makes sense.
我每天都看
I read that every day.
这是我父亲给我母亲的礼物
Gift from my father to my mother.
我母亲去世后把它留给了我
My mother left it to me after she passed.
拜托
Please.
来吧
Go ahead.
哪里疼
What's hurting?
我的脚踝伤得很严重
I messed up my ankle real bad.
老实坐好
Sit your fine ass down.
她伤了腿  可能骨折了
She hurt her leg. It could be broken.
所以呢
So?
她是我最好的朋友  而我是个护士
She's my best friend, and I'm a nurse.
你要操心的事还不够多吗
Don't you have enough to worry about?
那倒是  动作快点
True. Just do it quick.
别使劲  好吗  都交给我
Don't help, okay? I'll do all the work.
我要把你的靴子脱了
I'm gonna take your boot off.
我明白
I see.
像这样动一动腿
Move your leg like this.
再动动脚趾
Your toes?
应该没有骨折
Yeah, I don't think it's a break.
但扭伤很严重
But it's a pretty bad sprain. -
你之前在抗议吗
Were you protesting?
我是贵宾厅的招待  你呢
I'm a VIP hostess. And you?
我...
Um... I was...
我在帮一个朋友
helping a friend.
-这太扯了  -抓到卢克·凯奇了吗
- This is some bullshit. - You got Luke Cage?
拜托  那黑鬼是真人版刀枪不入的胡迪尼
Please. That nigga's on that bulletproof Houdini shit for real.
楼下呢
What about downstairs?
厨房没有路能下去
There's no way downstairs from the kitchen.
是你朋友卢克·凯奇吗
Is your friend Luke Cage?
-你认识他吗  -想忘都难
- Do you know him? - Hard to forget.
他以前在这里工作
He used to work here.
整件事都是我的错
This whole thing is my fault.
怎么了  发生什么事了
Hey... what's happening? What's wrong?
我做了些非常糟的事
I did something really bad.
她怎么了
What's wrong with her?
她很痛
She's in a lot of pain.
告诉我
Tell me.
我吓坏了
I was so scared.
他们花钱让我说我看到卢克杀了水腹蛇
They paid me to say I saw Luke kill Cottonmouth.
他们是谁
Who's they?
玛莉娅·迪拉德
Mariah Dillard.
你想帮卢克吗
You wanna help Luke?
那就告诉我他怎么从厨房消失的
Then you tell me how he could have disappeared from that kitchen
根本没人能从那里逃脱
that no one could've escaped from.
这栋楼是战前的违禁建筑
This is a prewar prohibition building.
下面有间储藏室
There's a storage space underneath.
员工常常会下去消磨时间
Employees used to go down there
或是在有大活动的时候
to fool around or sleep between shifts
趁换班时去睡一觉
when we had to prep a big event.
也就是在楼下的地下室  具体位置在哪
So it's downstairs in the basement? Where?
在员工储物柜旁边
By the staff lockers.
还有谁知道吗
Would anybody else know about that?
只有在厨房工作的人知道
Not unless they worked in the kitchen.
我是这里唯一的服务人员
I'm the only person from the waitstaff here...
还有卢克
except Luke.
要进出那个储藏室
The only way in or out of that storage room
唯一的路就是通过厨房
is through the kitchen.
卢克可以砸出另一扇门
Luke can make another door.
好吧  我需要你晕过去
Okay, I'm gonna need you to pass out.
-什么  -我需要你晕过去
- What? - I need you to pass out.
我会把我们带出去的
I'm gonna get us out of this.
我的天
Oh... Oh, my God!
-帮帮我们  -又怎么了
- Help us! - What now?
-她有糖尿病  -她的药呢
- She's diabetic. - Where's her shit?
肯定在楼下的员工储物柜里
Uh, it must be in, uh, the staff locker downstairs.
洛佩斯  陪夜班护士到楼下去
Yo, Lopes. Escort the night nurse here downstairs.
谢谢
Thank you.
你照顾她一下好吗
Will you look after her?
我很快回来  好吗
I'll be right back, okay?
好的  亲爱的
Okay, baby.
-就在这下面  -快点
- Just down here. -Just hurry up.
你死不了
You'll live.
那么  你这个哥哥到底想干什么
So, what does this brother of yours want, anyway?
复仇
Revenge.
他陷害了我  害我进了海门监狱
He framed me. He sent me to Seagate.
他想把这个劫持人质的事都栽在你头上
He's trying to pin this whole hostage thing on you.
也是他诬陷你杀了水腹蛇吗
Did he set you up for Cottonmouth's murder, too?
真是他我也不会意外
I wouldn't put it past him.
只有你知道真相
You're the only one that knows the truth.
等我们出去  我需要你的帮助
I'll need your help when we get out of this.
没问题
You'll have it.
-我们得进去了  -得先有个计划才行
- We need to go in. - Not until we have a plan.
凯奇非常强壮  而且刀枪不入
Cage is super strong and bulletproof.
我们坐得越久  这疯子就越有底
The longer we sit, the more entrenched this lunatic gets.
我们之前跟一个人质通上了话
We've had exactly one conversation with a hostage,
达蒙·布恩  那个政客  结果被切断了
Damon Boone, the politician, and we got cut off.
我也同意进去  可我们得先计划好
Now, I am with you on going in, but we need a plan.
我们以前没经历过这种事
We've never faced anything like this before.
瑞德里探长  我是地检官布莱克·托尔
Inspector Ridley? Blake Tower, DA's Office.
-托尔先生  怎么了  -您来告诉我
- Mr. Tower. What's going on? - You tell me.
我们一直在密切关注凯奇的动向
We've been closely following Cage's activities.
市长会希望我帮忙协调的
The mayor would like me to help coordinate.
-已经协调好了  -是吗
- The situation is coordinated. - Really?
我们是同一边的
We're on the same side...
我想指导你们如何最好地达成
...and I'd like to guide you as how best to achieve an outcome
对各方都有利的结果
that's beneficial to all parties.
最有利的结果
Yeah, the most beneficial outcome
就是我把人质和我的警探活着带出来
is for me to get those hostages and my detective out alive,
并给卢克·凯奇带上手铐
and Luke Cage in cuffs.
这些你都给不了我
None of which you can give me.
-探长  -怎么
- Inspector? - Yeah.
有人确认
We have independent confirmation
爆炸是来自内部的
that the explosion came from inside.
-现在能进去了吗  -我们等着
- Now can we go in? - We wait.
万一他直接把这些人都开枪打死了呢
What if he just shoots all those people dead?
那不是凯奇的做法
That is not Cage's MO.
我们每次与他交锋  他从来没使用过枪
Every encounter we've ever had with him, he's never used a gun.
他根本不用
He doesn't have to.
他现在开始用了吧
Well, he's using one now, isn't he?
我看过那个车载视频
Well, I saw that dashcam video.
他几秒钟就能干掉你整个小队
He can take out your whole team in mere seconds
而且毫发无伤
and not get a scratch.
我同意
I agree.
为了拿下这个混蛋  我们必须加大警力
In order to engage this asshole, we need to bring the heat.
你有什么主意吗  助理地检先生
You got any ideas Mr., uh, ADA?
市长现在正在闭门
Look, the mayor is in a closed-door session
是否应该加强执法部门配备的武器
discussing enhanced weapons for law enforcement.
和谁
With who?
玛莉娅·迪拉德
Mariah Dillard.
怎么了
What's wrong?
得系紧点
It needs to be tighter.
振作一点
Brace yourself.
一
One...
我感觉我要像克里斯珀斯·阿塔克斯一样了
I feel like getting my Crispus Attucks on up there.
你聪明多了
You gotta be smart about this.
外面有太多无辜的民众
There are too many innocent people up there
可能会丧命
who could end up dead.
我也许别无选择
I might not have a choice.
我曾经有选择
I had a choice.
我应该相信你的
I should have trusted you.
我知道
I know.
这样说也没法让我好受
You didn't make it easy.
别去干蠢事
Don't go doing anything stupid.
比如什么
Like what?
逞英雄
Be a hero.
我不是什么英雄
I'm not the hero type.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
在我看来你一直都是
Looks to me like that's what you've always been.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
你为什么不离开那个酒吧
Why the hell didn't you leave the club?
我什么时候乖乖听过话
When have I ever done as I was told?
米丝蒂  米丝蒂
Misty! Misty!
是  长官  当然了
Yes, sir. Absolutely.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们也许有办法对付卢克·凯奇了
We might have something to take Luke Cage out.
一种尚未得到授权的试验型武器
An experimental weapon that's never been authorized before.
-有人在暗中操纵  是你吗  -不
- Someone's pulling strings. Is that you? - No.
那就是  玛莉娅·迪拉德  你帮她联系睡了吗
Then it's Mariah Dillard. Did you put her in touch with someone?
布恩又来电了
It's Boone again.
布恩先生  你没事吧
Mr. Boone. Are you okay?
卢克·凯奇想告诉你他的要求
Luke Cage would like to give you his demands.
我们洗耳恭听
We're listening.
他要你往屋顶上派一辆直升机
He wants a chopper on the roof.
为表诚意  凯奇先生愿意
As a sign of goodwill, Mr. Cage is willing
在电话结束后释放一半人质
to let half the hostages go at the end of this call.
留下我和其他一部分人  确保他能顺利逃脱
Me and a few others will remain to ensure his escape.
我们马上去办
We will get right on that.
奈特警官还活着吗
Is Detective Knight still alive?
是的  她还活着
Yes. Yes, she is.
我们需要证实她还活着  才能继续帮你们
We will need proof of life before we proceed.
不
No.
他说你没有资格提要求
He's saying you're not in a position to make demands.
那就有麻烦了
Well, then we have a problem.
他说马上释放一部分人质
He says a few hostages will be coming out now.
-明白  -他在拖时间
- Got it! - He's stalling.
我知道她在干什么  他可以直接杀出去的
I know what he's doing. He could just want a way out.
我们得继续拖住他  直到新武器运到
We should keep on stalling him until the new weapons show up.
我只接受局长的命令
I take my orders from the chief.
到底怎么回事
What's really going on here?
我想让我们用一种
Do I want us to use a weapon
能干掉刀枪不入者的武器吗
that can take out a man that's bulletproof?
-当然不想了  -我不明白
- Absolutely not. - I don't understand.
警方或军队所使用的武器
Look, any weapon that the police or military has
最后都会出现在街头
eventually ends up on the street.
你应该知道即使只是展示一下威力都很危险
You know it's dangerous to even show that kind of power.
但我觉得我们别无选择
Hey, but I don't see we got much of a choice.
-我不信任玛莉娅·迪拉德  -我也不信
- I don't trust Mariah Dillard. - Yeah, I don't either.
但她打通了我们上级的关系
But she has juice with people way above our paygrade.
我只是不想
I just don't want this
让这演变成OK牧场的大枪战
to turn into the Gunfight at the O.K. Corral.
弗兰克·卡塞尔让整个城市变为抵御
Frank Castle shot the city to hell,
他也只有普通的子弹
and he only had regular bullets.
想象一下万一他这种人用这种武器能干什么
Now imagine what he or somebody like him can do with these things.
我明白  你在这里没看到谁
Yeah, I hear you. Who is the one person you don't see here?
局长
A chief.
那是什么意思  他要保持距离  推诿
And what does that tell you? He wants distance. Deniability.
如果出错  负责的就是我
If this goes wrong, the blood is on my hands,
-只有我  -探长
- and mine alone. - Inspector.
门打开了
There's movement at the door.
小心  他出来了  不要开火
Eyes up. He's coming out. Hold fire.
手  把你们的手举起来
Hands! Hands! Put your hands in the air!
往前走
Step forward.
快  我们走  我们走
Come on, let's go! Let's go!
-快点  -没错  这边走  快
- Move it, come on! - That's right. This way! Go, go!
安全
We're clear.
-带他们离开这里  -跟我来
- Get them out of here. Come on. - Follow me.
直接贯穿了
Well, it went clean through.
你失血过多
You've lost a lot of blood.
我在那种情况下
I handled the situation the best I could
已经尽力处理了  克莱尔
under the circumstances, Claire.
她没被轰飞胳膊算你走运
Yeah, you're lucky she didn't lose her arm.
离伤口太近了
That is way too close to the wound.
我只会治病  你只会防弹
Me, medical shit. You, bulletproof shit.
你们听上去都结婚了
Y'all sound married.
很好
That's good.
我去拿点东西
I'm gonna get some stuff.
我妈妈喜欢白人灵魂音乐
Oh, my mama loved blue-eyed soul.
你要是有机会见我母亲黛娜就好了
I wish you could have met Dana...my mother.
-她很美  -是的
- She's beautiful. - Yes.
她曾是一个著名牧师的秘书
She was a secretary for a big-time preacher.
他是一个大胆自信有魅力的人
A bold, charismatic man who...
喜欢高谈阔论  衣着光鲜
loved to talk loud and dress fancy.
-跟你一样  -是的
- Like you. - Exactly.
他们一起工作的时间很长  很有压力
They worked long, stressful hours and...
他们在后勤办公室度过了很多愉快的日子
Well, they had a lot of laughter in that back office.
注定要发生一些事  然后
Something was bound to happen and...
就发生了
it did.
我出生了
I was born.
但他已经结婚了
But he was married.
本来一切都很好
And everything was good...
直到牧师的妻子在两年后生了一个儿子
until the preacher's wife, two years later, had a baby boy.
一个奇迹般的孩子
A miracle child.
所以一切都变了
And everything changed.
伟大的卢卡斯牧师
The great Reverend Lucas
没胆让自己的大儿子跟自己姓
wasn't man enough to give his first son his last name.
所以我仍然是威利斯·斯崔克
You see, I was still Willis Stryker.
但他真正的儿子
But his real son...
是卡尔·卢卡斯
was Carl Lucas.
但是  扯淡的是
But... here's the crazy thing.
没人说什么
Nobody said nothing.
卡尔和我
And Carl and I...
我们从小就是好朋友  但是
we grew up best friends, but...
我们之间却有一种无形的竞争
there was all this tension.
你能真真切切感觉到
You could just feel it
就像一阵风从门那边传来
like a draft coming in from under a door.
我只想让他看到我
I just wanted him to see me.
我是个好孩子
I was a good boy.
我学习成绩很好
I did well in school.
但他总是更爱卡尔
But he always loved Carl more.
探长  借一步说话
Inspector? A word?
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
一些人质的证词跟我们所知的情况不符
Some of the hostages' statements are not matching up.
大部分人说的是看到里面的人朝凯奇开枪
Most are saying that they saw people inside shooting at Cage,
不是凯奇朝他们
not the other way around.
我们可能搞错了
We might have this all wrong.
有这个可能
We might.
一会儿我们有时间弄清楚到底是怎么回事
We'll have time to get to the bottom of what's going on later.
但现在我们需要控制住这一局面
But right now, we need to get control of this situation,
目前我们还没有控制权
and we are not in control yet.
你  不要四处看了
You! Stop looking around!
-第一批人质出去了  -很好
- The first of the hostages are gone. - Good.
你不担心他们会说什么吗
You're not worried about what they're gonna say?
等有人弄明白
By the time anyone figures out the truth,
哈莱姆的威胁就已经死了
Harlem's Menace will be dead
否则就是我死
or I will.
我不会去作证的  你呢
I ain't testifying. Are you?
我为什么要作证
Why would I?
你真的想让我确认你根本没有计划吗
Would you really want me to confirm that you had no plan?
你想想那样会让我们两个人看起来多蠢
Think about how stupid that would make both of us look.
你忘记自己在跟谁说话了吗
Have you forgotten who you're talking to?
你忘了吗
Have you?
-你说的直升机呢  -拜托
- What about the helicopter? - Please.
他们肯定不会同意
There's no way they'll agree to that.
我知道
I know.
什么事
What happened?
-洛佩斯被人从楼梯上推下来了  -什么
- Lopes got pushed down the stairs. - What?
一个人质晕倒了
One of the hostages passed out,
另一个去拿药品
and another one went to go get her medication.
-哪个人质  -贵宾室的服务生
- Which hostage? - The waitress from VIP.
西印长相的那个妞
The West Indian-lookin' chick.
坎迪斯  天啊
Candace. God...
-另一个找到了吗  -没有
- Did you find the other one? - No.
我和响尾蛇还没说完话  糖糖
Diamondback and I aren't finished speaking, Sugar.
所以你们都先回避一下
So I'm gonna need y'all to fall back.
是我不好
My bad.
怎么了
What?
玛莉娅就是利用坎迪斯
Candace is the one that Mariah used
把水腹蛇谋杀案扣到了卢克·凯奇头上
to pin Cottonmouth's murder on Luke Cage.
-另一个  -可能就是在诊所捅我的那个人
- The other one-- - Is probably the one who stabbed me at the clinic.
该死  我就说她看着眼熟
Damn it. I knew she looked familiar.
她可能是跟凯奇一起进来的
She probably came in with Cage.
坎迪斯知道凯奇长什么样
Candace knows what Cage looks like.
另一个跟他一起的妞  如果让她逃了
The other chick with him, if she escapes...
她们任何一个人都可能揭穿我们的幌子
Either one of them could blow our cover story.
-她们都得处理掉  -那就去处理掉
- They all got to go. - Take care of it then.
你和我  等这件事结束
You and me, we get out of this...
我们要促膝长谈一番
we're gonna have a long talk.
你好好记着
Best believe that.
我们去楼下
Let's go. Downstairs.
卡尔  卡尔  卡尔
Carl, Carl, Carl.
你又这样了
Here you go again.
躲躲藏藏  就因为你太胆小不敢正面应战
Bobbing and weaving because you're too scared to take a hit.
就跟我教你打的拳一样
It's just like I taught you in the ring.
不管你怎么躲
No matter how much you duck,
最终你都要站出来的
eventually, you're gonna have to knuck and buck.
如果你自己和米丝蒂·奈特
If you don't surrender yourself...
不出来投降
and Misty Knight...
我要每十分钟杀一个人质
I'm gonna kill a hostage every ten minutes...
从达蒙·布恩开始
starting with Damon Boone.
他是认真的
He's not bluffing.
-我要去除掉他  -他设好陷阱在等你
- I gotta take him out. - You're walking into a trap.
-你很清楚  -正合我意
- You know that. - I'm counting on it.
要赢不总是要打一架
You don't always have to fight to win.
如果出问题  我们目前被警察包围了
Look, if things go south, we are surrounded by cops.
我会确保他们知道你是清白的
I'll make sure that they know you're innocent.
他们会知道真相  我保证
They'll know the truth, I promise.
不要为了我而死  米丝蒂
Don't go dying on me, Misty.
-有我在就不会的  -他基本上就是这一套
- Not on my watch. - Hmm. That's usually his line.
他们利用女服务员坎迪斯来陷害你
They used that waitress, Candace, to frame you.
混蛋骗子
Lyin' ass.
她在哪里
Where is she?
和其他人一起在楼上
Upstairs with the others.
如果他有更多的这种特殊的子弹怎么办
What if he has more of those special bullets?
我也只能冒险
That's a chance I'll have to take.
如果我陷入了麻烦  你必须要保护好自己
If I don't walk away from this, you need to lay in the cut
除非你得到了波比·菲什或者米丝蒂的消息
until you hear from me, Bobby Fish or Misty.
其他人都不可信
No one else.
-你知道我很服从命令的  -我是认真的
- You know how well I follow orders. - I'm serious.
威利斯是认真的
Willis plays for keeps...
尤其对我最在乎的人下手
especially with people I care about the most.
答应我
Promise me.
我会的
I will.
-你有可以躲的地方吗  -有的
- You have a place in mind? - Yeah.
你要小心
Be careful.
一直如此
Always.
真是多愁善感
You're so corny.
就这样别动  胳膊朝上
Keep that right there, okay? Arm turned up.
我操
Shit!
你可以先提醒我的
You could've warned me.
是  我本来可以的
Yeah, I could've.
告诉我你接下来要做什么
Talk me through what you're about to do.
好的  我马上要用这个牙线
Okay. I am gonna use this dental floss...
给你的手臂静脉
to tie off your...
-打个结 -我感觉我要吐了
- hosing vein. - I think I'm gonna throw up.
这里
There.
这可以切断你手掌和小臂的血液输送
This is gonna cut the blood supply to your hand and your forearm.
它在你体内越久
The longer this stays in...
你失去手臂的可能性就越高
the higher the chances of losing your arm.
我想跟你道歉
Look, I want to apologize.
我不应该对你发脾气
I shouldn't have lost my cool with you.
这世道都疯了  你这么做也无可厚非
Ah, you can't be to blame with this kind of crazy.
感觉你已经非常习惯了
Well, you're in pretty deep.
是的  麻烦就像前男友一样不停地找上我
Yeah, well, trouble stalks me like a crazy ex-boyfriend.
我懂你
I hear you.
你和卢克去喝咖啡了吗
You and Luke go out for coffee yet?
我们还没时间去
Uh, we haven't had time.
他不喜欢喝咖啡
He doesn't like coffee.
我知道
I know.
弄好了
All done.
天啊  你真棒
Damn, you're good.
各司其职  各善其事
You're good at your job, I'm good at mine.
玛莉娅跟市长说过了  枪流行了起来
Mariah talked to the mayor. The guns are a go.
祝你好运  兄弟
Good luck, brother.
迪拉德议员一直在给我惊喜
Councilwoman Dillard never ceases to amaze me.
压力之下
Pressure...
有些人才会脱颖而出
brings the best out of certain people.
我说到哪了
So... where was I?
团结一心
Together...
我们所向披靡
we were bold.
就像歌里唱的  我们偷了一辆红色的克尔维特
We stole a red Corvette, just like the song...
去驾车游玩
just... for a joyride.
那时候我喜欢普林斯
You see, I was a Prince fan, and...
卡尔最喜欢迈克尔
Carl was all about Michael.
我们忙着争吵  都没有看见警察
We were so busy arguing, we didn't even see the cop.
光芒
但是卡尔是卢卡斯But Carl was a Lucas.
悍将
我是斯崔克I was a Stryker.
还未开始  胜负已分
It was over before it even began.
到了法庭宣判的时候
When it came time for sentencing,
牧师劝说法官
the preacher convinced the judge
让他的宝贝孩子参加了海军陆战队
to let his golden boy join the Marines.
我呢
Me?
是个少年罪犯
Juvie.
经常卷入到各种斗殴之中
Got jumped two days in.
有个男孩拿着一把刀
Boy drew a shank and...
我出于自卫杀了他
...I killed him in self-defense.
从此我的好日子就到头了
So I got sent away to hard time.
至于亲爱的黛娜
And sweet Dana?
癌症吞噬了她  她只能在避难所
Oh, her cancer ate her alive and she died alone...
孤独地死去
in a shelter...
连个朋友都没有
without a friend in the world.
这个善良的牧师卢卡斯
You see, the good Reverend Lucas...
在我走之后也不再关心她了
well, he stopped caring for her after I was gone.
他抛弃了她
He was free of her...
我无能为力
and I was powerless.
但是她
But she, oh...
她仍然深爱着他
Oh, she still loved him...
而且她希望我能继承我爸爸的一些优点
and... well, she wanted me to have something of my father's.
上帝让我接触到了《创世纪》
God had me at hello with Genesis.
这就是该隐与亚伯的故事
The story of Cain and Abel.
当上帝问在该隐杀掉亚伯之后问他亚伯在哪时
When God asked Cain where Abel was after he killed him...
该隐问  "我是弟弟的守护者吗"
Cain asked, "Am I my brother's keeper?"
你看
See...
我以为这些很棒的东西都是
I thought that was some cool shit
韦斯利·斯奈普斯在《纽约黑街》里虚构的
Wesley Snipes made up in New Jack City.
最后发现
Turns out...
这是真的
it's real.
所以
So...
我杀了卢克·凯奇之后
after I kill Luke Cage...
我要踩在他身上说
I'm gonna stand over him and say,
"是的  我是"
"Yes, I am."
为什么你告诉我这些
Why are you telling me all this?
因为你要去见我的母亲了  达蒙
Because you're about to meet my mother, Damon.
告诉她我爱她
Tell her I love her.
沙兹  把布恩议员放在门口
Shades, show Councilman Boone to the door.
-门  -门开了
- Door! - Opening door!
举起手来
Put your hands in the air!
快上  我们上  散开  前进
Go, go, go. Let's go. Let's spread in. Move in.
快  抬他起来
Let's go, guys. Get him up. Get him up.
来人抬他的脚
Someone grab his feet.
他死了
He's dead.
胸口炸了一个大洞
Chest is caved in.
赶紧进去
Move in now.
特大新闻
哈莱姆议员被杀
已经证实
It has been confirmed
特大新闻
哈莱姆议员被杀
从出口扔出来的尸体
that the body thrown from the entrance
特大新闻
哈莱姆议员被杀
确实是来自哈莱姆的达蒙·布恩
was indeed Harlem's own, Damon Boone.
特大新闻
哈莱姆议员被杀
确实是来自哈莱姆的达蒙·布恩
was indeed Harlem's own, Damon Boone.
现在  我们还是不知道卢克·凯奇想要什么
At this time, we still have no clear idea what Luke Cage wants.
-怎么回事  -转过去
- What's going on? - Turn around.
我看卢克·凯奇来过这里
I see Luke Cage was here.
我来帮你
Let me help you.
好了
Okay.
你还有一手
You got skills.
彼此彼此
Likewise.
我父亲
My father.
我叔叔
My uncle.
好  继续等命令
All right. Still waiting on word.
希望他们知道这武器的威力
I hope they know what they're authorizing.
我们主要的目标应该是解救人质
Our main focus should be freeing the hostages.
除非必要  他们不应该开枪
They shouldn't shoot unless absolutely necessary.
我的人知道该怎么做  别废话了  让我们上
My men know the job. Stop meddling and let us get to work.
也许不是卢克·凯奇干的
Luke Cage might not be behind this.
等我看到他后我会问他的
I'll ask him when I see him.
谁都不许动
Nobody move.
我是认真的
I ain't playing.
这边
This way.
举着这个  把手举起来
Wave this. Keep your hands raised.
卡尔
Hey, Carl.
怎么了  哥哥
What's happening, brother?
特大新闻
超能力逃犯扣押人质
怎么了  哥哥
What's happening, brother?
特大新闻
超能力逃犯扣押人质
好像放出了更多人质
We have what looks like more hostages being released.
特大新闻
超能力逃犯扣押人质
紧急情况小队警官正在接近大楼出口
And ESU officers are approaching the building entrance
特大新闻
超能力逃犯扣押人质
紧急情况小队警官正在接近大楼出口
And ESU officers are approaching the building entrance
去找卢克·凯奇进行对峙
to allegedly confront Luke Cage.
-放开他  -我会的
- Let her go. - Oh, we'll get to that.
我们很久以前就应该讲和
Couldn't we have made amends a long time ago?
你小时候就该去死
Couldn't you have died during childbirth?
冷静点
Easy there.
对于黛娜的事我很遗憾
I was sorry to hear about Dana.
我一直很喜欢她
I always liked her.
我完全忍受不了埃特  真是个贱人
I couldn't stand Etta. What a bitch!
我们有致命的武器  凯奇
We have lethal rounds, Cage
-我们会使用它们  -该走了
- We will use them. - Gotta go.
你杀了那名人质后
With that hostage you killed,
他们肯定会先开枪再问问题
they're gonna shoot first and ask questions later.
玛莉娅给那些军队提供了犹大升级版
Mariah supplied the force with some Judas 2.0s,
这样就不会从你身上弹开
so they won't bounce off of you.
而是会直破你的皮肤
They'll stick.
你要跑吗  小甜心
You gonna run, Miracle Whip?
还是说你想救这名少女
Or you gonna save the damsel?
威利斯
Willis.
再见  卡尔
Bye, Carl.
再见  菲利希亚
Bye, Felicia.
快快快  进去
Go, go! Get in there!
对不起  卢克
I'm sorry, Luke.
进去  我们看到了
Move in! We have visual.
把手举起来
Hands in the air!
你听到了  别动
You heard him. Don't move.
举起来
In the air!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
-你想离开这里吗  -是的
- You want to get out of here, right? - Yeah.
好  这边走  这边走
Okay. This way. This way.
我说赶紧举起手来
I said in the air, now!
-你有车吗  -水腹蛇有三辆
- Hey, you got a ride? - Cottonmouth had three.
起作用了
It worked.
他们抓到了他  根本不用开枪
They got him. Didn't even have to fire.
那才是最重要的  这些武器会改变一切
That's all that matters. Those weapons are a game changer.
-希望永远用不上  -探长
- Hope we never have to use them. - Inspector.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
听着  卢克·凯奇是无辜的
Listen, Luke Cage is innocent.
事情并不像你们所见的这样
What you think you saw is not what happened.
你不如先专心养好身体
Why don't you focus on getting fixed up?
让我们来收拾乱子吧
Let us clean up this mess.
都是威利斯·斯崔克惹出来的  是他朝我开枪
This mess is Willis Stryker's doing. He's the one who shot me.
听着  他叫响尾蛇
Listen, his name is Diamondback.
我相信你  米丝蒂
I believe you, Misty.
我们还要找很多人谈话
There are dozens of other people to talk to.
卢克还要为阿尔比尼之死
And Luke is still wanted for Albini's murder,
水腹蛇之死  和袭警负责
Cottonmouth's murder, and attacking those cops.
你没听明白
You are not listening to me.
卢克·凯奇是完全无辜的
Luke Cage is innocent of everything.
等我们羁押他后  我们会证实的
And after we have him in custody, we'll verify it.
听着  我相信你
Look... I trust you.
真的
I do.
但我们得证实
But we have to verify.
唯一重要的事  就是真相
The only thing that matters is the truth.
没事的  警探  让我看看你的手臂
We got you, Detective. Let me look at your arm.
不管你要干什么  在这里赶紧了事
Listen, whatever you need to do, you need to do it right here.
我哪儿也不去  还不能走
Okay? I'm not going anywhere. Not yet.
我们走
Let's go.
那是卢克·凯奇
Yo! That's Luke Cage!
-快看  -就是他
- Check him out, man! - That's him!
那是卢克
Yo, B! There go Luke!
我们知道你是无辜的  卢克
We know you innocent, Luke!
快走
Go.